<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blog.dbljump.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blog.dbljump.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-01-27T22:45:03+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.dbljump.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dbljump Blog</title><subtitle>Dbljump is on a mission to build the world's best video game reference. Read updates and opinion from our team.</subtitle><author><name>Dbljump Team</name></author><entry><title type="html">APA-style referencing comes to Dbljump</title><link href="https://blog.dbljump.com/2022/01/26/apa-style-referencing-comes-to-dbljump/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="APA-style referencing comes to Dbljump" /><published>2022-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.dbljump.com/2022/01/26/apa-style-referencing-comes-to-dbljump</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.dbljump.com/2022/01/26/apa-style-referencing-comes-to-dbljump/">&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Dbljump articles now feature references in the widely-used APA style of academic citation. As an editor, it’s easy to reference many kinds of resources and add multiple sources for each part of your article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/01/library-books.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good referencing is really important to us here at Dbljump, so I’m really happy to announce that articles on games, people, and companies now feature APA-style referencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-is-referencing-important&quot;&gt;Why is referencing important?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re striving to build something important for gaming with Dbljump - a resource you can trust, which honours and respects creators, and keeps high standards for compiling and presenting information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referencing is really important in achieving these goals because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It makes the information in Dbljump articles verifiable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It allows you, the reader, to easily find and read sources yourself. A Dbljump article should provide a comprehensive summary on its topic. With good referencing, you can dive further into the details.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It enables us to credit the primary sources used by Dbljump - the journalists, the researchers, the archivists - and help they reach a wider audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-apa-referencing&quot;&gt;What is APA referencing?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve chosen the APA (American Psychological Association) citation style for Dbljump. Although it was designed for the field of psychology, it’s used today in many fields of science and humanities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APA references look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;McWhertor, M. (2020, December 10). Capcom’s making a new
    Ghosts ’n Goblins. Polygon. Vox Media, LLC.
    https://www.polygon.com/some-uri.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our APA styling is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://owl.purdue.edu/owl/research_and_citation/apa_style/apa_formatting_and_style_guide/general_format.html&quot;&gt;Purdue University’s guide to APA 7&lt;/a&gt;. We don’t have a perfect implementation yet, but we’ll improve it over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-add-references-to-an-article&quot;&gt;How do you add references to an article?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the move to support APA, we’ve revamped Dbljump’s tools for creating and editing encyclopaedia-like content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When adding or editing an article paragraph, you can now use a simple form to add multiple sources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose from six currently-supported media types: web article, website, web page, YouTube video, book, or print article.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the URL.  If it’s already referenced by another article, you can link it to the article you’re working on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill in a set of form fields appropriate to the type of source you’re referencing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/01/check-url.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      If the resource you’re citing is already on Dbljump, just link it

    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/01/cite-book.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      You can easily add information for each kind of reference

    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-we-improve-this&quot;&gt;How can we improve this?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve just launched this feature and we’d love for you to try it and let us know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, we plan to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Validate URLs before saving, to make sure they’re loading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check source URLs against a deny list of websites before saving, to reduce spam and poor-quality references&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support more kinds of media, like non-YouTube videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support page numbers for print media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can let us know what you think via Twitter or our Facebook page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-can-create-well-cited-gaming-articles-with-dbljump-now&quot;&gt;You can create well-cited gaming articles with Dbljump now!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely, Dbljump is becoming a unique platform for organising and sharing video gaming knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can only achieve our mission with your help. Register now to join the community and try these new features!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://id.dbljump.com/register&quot;&gt;Register as an editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Neil Wheatley</name></author><summary type="html">Dbljump articles now feature references in the widely-used APA style of academic citation. As an editor, it's easy to add multiple sources to your article content.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Smarter than AI, more valuable than oil - it’s the Dbljump community, join us!</title><link href="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/12/09/smarter-than-ai-more-valuable-than-oil-community/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smarter than AI, more valuable than oil - it's the Dbljump community, join us!" /><published>2021-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/12/09/smarter-than-ai-more-valuable-than-oil-community</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/12/09/smarter-than-ai-more-valuable-than-oil-community/">&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; We recently ran our first data scraping project - which was a reminder that (1) our user community, not raw data, is the most valuable thing we have, and (2) Dbljump needs to be more than just a game database to succeed. Will you join us?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021/12/dbljump-community.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some people say data is the new oil&lt;/strong&gt;. As in, the new Most Valuable Thing to be in the business of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been working on a metadata scraping project within Dbljump. With data scraping, I’ve added around 1,400 company records to the database. It’s much faster than doing it by hand. Each record is a stub for a new Dbljump article, and having them in place is useful for creating game credits and other relationships. I also learned some Python along the way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data scraping is really useful and we’ll continue to do it. It’s important to our mission. If we’re successful, one day other projects will be scraping “our” data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the course of my first data scraping project, I was also reminded that pure data is not the Most Valuable Thing for Dbljump. It’s not our oil, our fuel, or our primary resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most valuable thing to Dbljump is actually you&lt;/strong&gt; - our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I don’t mean your personal data. We don’t have any interest in that.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is community better than data? Because having lots of games industry data isn’t actually that valuable. No matter how beautifully it’s presented, it’s still just data that doesn’t really belong to anyone. And by itself, it doesn’t make for an interesting service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve believed this from the very start of the Dbljump project – and that’s why I’ve always thought Dbljump needs to be more than a gaming database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-difference-between-dbljump-and-game-databases&quot;&gt;The difference between Dbljump and game databases&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at one of the more-complete pages on Dbljump - like our article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://alpha.dbljump.com/games/ghosts-n-goblins-resurrection&quot;&gt;Ghosts ‘n Goblins Resurrection&lt;/a&gt; - and compare it to what game database sites have for the same title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the difference?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like game database sites, the Dbljump page has structured metadata, images, and credits. Structured data is obviously a big part of what makes a service like Dbljump useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you’ll see &lt;strong&gt;most of the page is made up of written content&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read the page like an article. Dive into the details. And click through to sources, which give you even more depth (and properly credit other creators). This encyclopaedia-like content is unique and written by Dbljump community members like you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two reasons why Dbljump is designed like this, with written content playing such an important role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structured metadata doesn’t tell the full story&lt;/strong&gt;. It can’t describe how news of Resurrection’s development was leaked, or what the series creator’s goal was. Only written content can do that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can only make something new and better&lt;/strong&gt; by creating this kind of rich and unique content. Game database projects that are focused on metadata already exist, but they fall short of what we want from a gaming knowledge centre. That’s one reason we’re building Dbljump.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings us to why community is the Most Valuable Thing for Dbljump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;only-a-community-can-achieve-our-mission&quot;&gt;Only a community can achieve our mission&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes people - not just bots, scripts, or data models - to build something worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dbljump is very much a software project. There’s a big stack of technologies it can’t even exist without. But I believe technology is just a tool for people to use. It’s only ever one part of a good solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the plan has never been to create this big automated data harvester. We don’t think AI or machine learning can write good content. The mission isn’t to exploit and extract value and profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No, Dbljump’s mission really is to build the world’s best video game knowledge reference&lt;/strong&gt;. And we can only do it with your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t want to take ownership of the content you create with Dbljump either. All Dbljump content will be published via Creative Commons licensing. As we grow, we also want to share the wealth and give you ways to present the research and writing you do as a Dbljump editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-only-take-a-minute-to-join&quot;&gt;It only take a minute to join!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dbljump is working to become the best place on the Internet to find anything you want to know about games, gaming companies, industry people, and more. We’ll get there much faster with your help, and you could meet interesting people and learn new things along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why not join us? You can register as an editor now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And feel free to reach out to me directly with any questions or comments via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; DMs or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; messaging. I really love to hear from anyone insterested in our project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people think data is the new oil. Well, the Dbljump community wants to welcome you - and we wouldn’t trade you for a hundred barrels!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://id.dbljump.com/register&quot;&gt;Register as an editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Neil Wheatley</name></author><summary type="html">A recent data scraping project reminded us of the huge value of community and why Dbljump needs to be more than a game database.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Share your Brave Rewards with Dbljump - and help make Internet ads safer and better</title><link href="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/11/02/contribute-brave-rewards-to-dbljump/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Share your Brave Rewards with Dbljump - and help make Internet ads safer and better" /><published>2021-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/11/02/contribute-brave-rewards-to-dbljump</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/11/02/contribute-brave-rewards-to-dbljump/">&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Dbljump is now a verified Brave Rewards creator, which means you can support our mission just by using the excellent Brave browser. Brave has great privacy features and non-intrusive ads, and users receive BAT cryptocurrency payments each month. We hope you’ll try it and inlcude Dbljump in your monthly tips!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021/11/brave-rewards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brave is my favourite web browser and today I set up my Brave Rewards to contribute a chunk of my monthly payout to Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not familiar with Brave, it’s a browser based on Google Chromium that has good privacy features. It also offers &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/brave-rewards/&quot;&gt;Brave Rewards&lt;/a&gt;, an ad program that pays you in &lt;a href=&quot;https://basicattentiontoken.org/&quot;&gt;the cryptocurrency BAT (Basic Attention Token)&lt;/a&gt; just for having ads switched on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If enough people start using Brave and Brave Rewards, we might all have a safer Internet, with fewer annoying ads, and our favourite content creators could be paid more for their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t been asked to say any of this, but please - &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/&quot;&gt;try Brave&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-does-brave-rewards-pay&quot;&gt;How much does Brave Rewards pay?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I usually receive around 3 BAT (roughly $3 USD) per month from using Brave. I can either pay it into a crypto wallet, or choose sites I want to contribute to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not a huge amount, but it’s enough to tip my favourite sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia is an obvious choice for me to contribute to. I already &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikimediafoundation.org/support/&quot;&gt;donate&lt;/a&gt; every year, because I use the site almost every day for work or just to look up things that interest me. It’s an incredible resource and a huge inspiration for Dbljump. I feel we’re very lucky to have it on our very commercialised Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dbljump-is-now-a-verified-brave-rewards-creator&quot;&gt;Dbljump is now a verified Brave Rewards creator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021/11/brave-tip-box.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-right&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope one day you’ll feel the same about Dbljump as I do about Wikipedia. We’re working as smartly and as quickly as we can to build a gaming knowledge centre you’ll love. One that’s going to be even better than Wikipedia… for gaming, at least!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ll choose to contribute some of your Brave Rewards to Dbljump too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re now a Verified Creator at Brave. So, all you need to do is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Rewards button in the address bar while you’re at &lt;a href=&quot;dbljump.com&quot;&gt;dbljump.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then, either choose “Send Tip”, or switch on “Include in Auto-Contribute”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for supporting us!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Neil Wheatley</name></author><summary type="html">Dbljump is now a verified Brave Rewards creator. You can now support us by contributing your Brave Rewards BAT tokens. Brave is cleaning up Internet ads and protecting user privacy, and we hope you'll give the Brave browser a try!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New user settings have arrived - try them out now</title><link href="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/09/24/new-user-settings-have-arrived/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New user settings have arrived - try them out now" /><published>2021-09-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/09/24/new-user-settings-have-arrived</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/09/24/new-user-settings-have-arrived/">&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Announcing new user features at Dbljump including profile picture uploads, non-binary gender settings, auto-redirects after logging in, and login email changes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you registered as a Dbljump editor yet? If you have, you might have noticed a few missing features at our user settings site &lt;a href=&quot;https://id.dbljump.com&quot;&gt;id.dbljump.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good news - we just added a raft of features that you probably expected to be there already!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;video controls=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/images/2021/09/gender-input.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot; /&gt;
    Sorry, your browser doesn't support embedded .webm videos.
  &lt;/video&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;One of our new user profile controls&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload, change, and remove your profile picture&lt;/strong&gt; - feel like you’re in the future yet?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set your location and gender&lt;/strong&gt; - choose binary options or type whatever you want&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be taken back to the page you clicked ‘Log in’ from&lt;/strong&gt; - automatically as if by magic!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set a new login email&lt;/strong&gt; - you’ll be asked to confirm it before you can start using it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run into any bugs, problems, or just want to let us know what you think, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;tweet us&lt;/a&gt; or talk to us via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;our Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here ends this short announcement. Want to join our mission to organise the world’s gaming knowledge? &lt;a href=&quot;https://id.dbljump.com/register&quot;&gt;Sign up here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Neil Wheatley</name></author><summary type="html">Announcing new user features at Dbljump including profile picture uploads, non-binary gender settings, auto-redirects after logging in, and login email changes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dev diary: article fixes are here, web resources and game details coming soon</title><link href="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/08/24/dev-diary-article-fixes-web-resources-game-details/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dev diary: article fixes are here, web resources and game details coming soon" /><published>2021-08-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-08-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/08/24/dev-diary-article-fixes-web-resources-game-details</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/08/24/dev-diary-article-fixes-web-resources-game-details/">&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve fixed and improved many Dbljump article features and we’re working on new ones, including web resources and game details.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021/08/zelda-article.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We deployed a new version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://alpha.dbljump.com/&quot;&gt;the Dbljump public reference&lt;/a&gt; last week, which brings lots of fixes and improvements - and takes us another step closer towards achieving &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.dbljump.com/&quot;&gt;our mission&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dbljump wasn’t Showtime-Ready when we first launched a few months ago, and it isn’t now. But that’s ok. Our current phase is about trying things out in production, sharing what we’re working on, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://id.dbljump.com/register&quot;&gt;inviting you to get involved&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve rewritten a LOT of the dbljump.com reference, but here are some of the most noticeable improvements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game release dates work.&lt;/strong&gt; They now display correctly in the article header. The earliest release place is shown in the versions table. And you get a comprehensive list of dates, places, and platforms in the details section of each game article.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We split the site in two.&lt;/strong&gt; The public reference and content editing tools now have separate homes at alpha.dbljump.com and editor.dbljump.com. This has made the public reference application much smaller and simpler, which means it loads faster. Separating concerns like this means we can work towards much more focused designs for each site.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can now read from the top.&lt;/strong&gt; When you click through to a new page, you start at the top - not at the previous page’s scroll position like before.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metadata lists work.&lt;/strong&gt; We fixed problems with abbreviated lists like “Action, RPG, Fantasy, +3 more”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;404 errors work everywhere now.&lt;/strong&gt; You would previously get a blank screen when visiting a URL like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://alpha.dbljump.com/people/bad-link&lt;/code&gt;. Now you get helpful feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to see these changes in action, check out some of our more complete articles like &lt;a href=&quot;https://alpha.dbljump.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild&quot;&gt;Breath of the Wild&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://alpha.dbljump.com/games/ghosts-n-goblins-resurrection&quot;&gt;Ghosts ‘n Goblins Resurrection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, &lt;a href=&quot;https://id.dbljump.com/register&quot;&gt;why not sign up and create your own&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to know what you think of our progress so far. What do you like? Where are we totally failing? Tell us via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be reading your messages - and I’m ready for tough criticism! We really need your feedback to move forward in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps-web-resources-and-new-game-details&quot;&gt;Next steps: Web resources and new game details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we’re already working on bringing important new features to Dbljump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;better-referencing-and-external-links-with-web-resources&quot;&gt;Better referencing and external links with Web Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we’re building a new system for managing links and references, called Web Resources. Web Resources will allow us to properly cite sources for article notes, which is vital if we’re going to build a world-class reference. Web Resources will also allow us to &lt;strong&gt;add YouTube videos and trailers&lt;/strong&gt; to Dbljump articles, and to add official websites, Twitter pages, and other useful links to our articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded-game-details&quot;&gt;Expanded game details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also going to expand the kinds of technical details you can add to games. You can already specify display resolution, frame rates and a few other things that help you compare each platform version. We think it’s also important to add minimum and maximum &lt;strong&gt;player counts for offline, LAN, and Internet play&lt;/strong&gt;. And we’ll add other details, like I/O options, so that Dbljump articles can provide information about &lt;strong&gt;features like VR support and motion controls&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-involved&quot;&gt;Get involved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dbljump is a non-commercial technology project &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.dbljump.com/&quot;&gt;with a clear mission&lt;/a&gt;: to build the world’s best video game knowledge reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, we can achieve our mission much faster with your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to be involved in an ambitious video game data project, you want to build some useful experience, and you have some free time, feel free to get in touch. Some of the areas we need help with include web development (Ember.js, Ruby on Rails, data), community development, and business development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know the value of having a diverse team, and everyone is welcome to join in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, just reach out via our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Neil Wheatley</name></author><summary type="html">We've fixed and improved many Dbljump article features and we're working on new ones, including web resources and game details.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dbljump is 6 times faster with our new API</title><link href="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/07/16/dbljump-six-times-faster-new-api/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dbljump is 6 times faster with our new API" /><published>2021-07-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-07-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/07/16/dbljump-six-times-faster-new-api</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/07/16/dbljump-six-times-faster-new-api/">&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve launched a new version of the Dbljump API, which makes switching between articles faster than before. We now have the right data platform on which to build new features you can see and use, including better article pages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021/07/rails-jsonapi.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time you visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://alpha.dbljump.com&quot;&gt;the Dbljump video game reference&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll notice links between articles load much, much faster. It’s all thanks to our new API!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new API is made with &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubyonrails.org/&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt; 6, whereas previously we were on Rails 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the real reason for the speed boost is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jsonapi-serializer/jsonapi-serializer&quot;&gt;jsonapi-serializer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our API follows the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jsonapi.org/&quot;&gt;JSON:API&lt;/a&gt; specification. Previously, we used a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RubyGems&quot;&gt;Ruby gem&lt;/a&gt; called Active Model Serializers (AMS) to turn database records into JSON:API. But AMS is old and mothballed, while jsonapi-serializer is around &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/netflix/fast_jsonapi#performance-comparison&quot;&gt;25 times faster&lt;/a&gt; at serializing responses!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-an-api&quot;&gt;What’s an API?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An API (application programming interface) is a way for people or other applications to interact with an application. When a digital service needs to be used by various apps, having an API gives those apps a simple interface to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our  API lets dbljump.com fetch articles from the database, handles user logins, processes new data before its gets saved, and other things like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;speed-comparison&quot;&gt;Speed comparison&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to see the speed boost is by comparing the test suites of our old and new APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021/07/dbljump-api-test-speed-comparison.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software development, having an automated test suite is a way to make sure features stay workin over time. Adding new features or taking away old ones can unintentionally break other features. Testing flags broken features straight away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our old API test suite completed around 62 test assertions per second. But the new one handles 400 assertions per second. &lt;strong&gt;That’s 6.45 times faster!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-better-platform-for-building-new-features&quot;&gt;A better platform for building new features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new API has lots of other improvements too. So, it gives us a great foundation on which to build new Dbljump features you can see and use. We’ll have an update about new features soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, why not join &lt;strong&gt;our mission to build the world’s best video game reference&lt;/strong&gt; now? Choose how you want to get involved and click below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://id.dbljump.com/register&quot;&gt;Sign up as a Dbljump editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Contact us via Twitter if you’d like to join the team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Get our latest updates on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Neil Wheatley</name></author><summary type="html">Dbljump pages load much faster with our new API version, made with Ruby on Rails 6 and jsonapi-serializer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dbljump editor signups are open – here’s what you need to know</title><link href="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/03/16/dbljump-editor-signups-are-open/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dbljump editor signups are open -- here's what you need to know" /><published>2021-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/03/16/dbljump-editor-signups-are-open</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.dbljump.com/2021/03/16/dbljump-editor-signups-are-open/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021/03/dbljump-editor-community.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; You can now sign up to become a Dbljump editor! You’ll need to be approved before you can start editing. The project is evolving, and some features aren’t here yet, but as an editor you can help shape them. We plan to improve support materials for editors in the coming weeks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now &lt;a href=&quot;https://id.dbljump.com/register&quot;&gt;sign up&lt;/a&gt; to become an editor of Dbljump!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that Dbljump will grow into &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.dbljump.com/editor-community&quot;&gt;a friendly, active community&lt;/a&gt; that works together to create the world’s best video game reference. We’d love you to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things to know before you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;all-registrations-go-through-an-approval-process&quot;&gt;All registrations go through an approval process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021/03/signup-questionnaire.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-right&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to keep the Dbljump editor community small for the time being. Partly because we’re still in alpha, or early, development. And partly because we’re still figuring out how best to look after our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sign up, we’ll approve or decline your registration based on the answers you give in the questionnaire part of the form. This helps us keep numbers small and make sure editors can write confidently in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To improve your chance of being accepted&lt;/strong&gt;, please answer the questions on why and how you’ll contribute to Dbljump as fully as you can. We’ll let you know by email if you’ve been successful or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alpha--early-in-development&quot;&gt;Alpha = early in development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dbljump only just launched and we’re calling its current state an “alpha” release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What that means for you as an editor is that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some features aren’t here yet.&lt;/strong&gt; But if you become an editor, you can have a say on which features we develop next.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The database design isn’t set in stone.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s possible that things you create will be deleted as Dbljump evolves, but we’ll do our utmost to make sure that doesn’t happen. Most likely is that some metadata or past article versions will get lost at some point.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some features might might not work exactly as they should.&lt;/strong&gt; Tell us about bugs you encounter, so we can fix them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really want to hear about your experiences, good or bad. With your help, we’ll evolve Dbljump into a service that’s useful to read and great to contribute to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;editor-support-pages-are-coming-your-questions-and-feedback-will-help-us-create-them&quot;&gt;Editor support pages are coming. Your questions and feedback will help us create them.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn’t a lot of documentation about what to do as an editor yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your account is approved, you’ll log into your (quite-sparse-at-the-moment) dashboard and see tools for creating and editing articles about games, companies, and people. You can also upload images and add missing places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, how do you use these tools properly? We hope they’re intuitive enough, and you’re encouraged to simply try them out. But remember, this is an alpha test - and we’re going to use your feedback to evolve Dbljump editing tools so they’re just how you want them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we’d like you to just give it a go! If you’re not sure what to do, or you want to request that we change or improve something, &lt;strong&gt;you can always talk to us via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, or Discord&lt;/strong&gt;. I’m personally here to help in anyway I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the coming weeks and months, we’re going to be creating guides for editing Dbljump - first on this blog, and then on &lt;strong&gt;a dedicated support website&lt;/strong&gt;. All of your experiences and feedback will help us create useful docs, so keep experimenting and keep talking to us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thinking-of-signing-up&quot;&gt;Thinking of signing up?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to have you! Click below to learn more and sign up now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.dbljump.com/editor-community&quot;&gt;More about the editor community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://id.dbljump.com/register&quot;&gt;Register as a Dbljump editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Neil Wheatley</name></author><summary type="html">Learn about the editor registration approval process, the current project development phase, and coming support for editors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Dbljump?</title><link href="https://blog.dbljump.com/2020/06/15/what-is-dbljump/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Dbljump?" /><published>2020-06-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-06-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.dbljump.com/2020/06/15/what-is-dbljump</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.dbljump.com/2020/06/15/what-is-dbljump/">&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Dbljump is a mission to build the world’s best video game knowledge reference. It has the structure of a database, detailed prose like an encyclopaedia, and is 100% gaming focused. We’re launching an “alpha” version, with the goal of building the community and shaping development plans. Presentation and features will keep evolving with guidance from our community. This post will be updated when sign-ups open.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/2020/06/game-article.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Part of a game article on Dbljump&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020/06/game-article-th.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Part of a game article on Dbljump&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/2020/06/company-images-dashboard.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Managing images for a company article&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020/06/company-images-dashboard-th.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Managing images for a company article&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/2020/06/game-releases-dashboard.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Adding a release for a game. Specify platform, place, date and media.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020/06/game-releases-dashboard-th.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Adding a release for a game. Specify platform, place, date and media.&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to the Dbljump blog! This is our very first post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a kid I loved computer games (as we called them in 1990s England). As a grown-up, that hasn’t changed. Why would it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gaming is massive today. It’s a huge market, it’s popular everywhere, and it’s inspiring all kinds of creativity. But somehow, games have stayed far outside the establishment. It’s as if the medium is still too new to be trusted. Big players in the entertainment industries still don’t understand gaming. The press is still happy to vilify them. Some critics have said games can never be art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video games’ current standing reminds me of a lecture from my English degree. The lecture was about early novels. A few hundred years ago, reading novels was considered self-indulgent, a waste of time. Today, great novels are regarded as high art. That’s the journey all culture makes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of novels are worthless trash; many are fantastic. The same can be said of video games. There’s no doubt in my mind that in the future, games will be held in the same regard as literature, music and cinema. It’s going to take a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But some of us already appreciate the wonder and importance of video games. If you’re one of them, Dbljump is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dbljump-is-a-video-game-knowledge-reference&quot;&gt;Dbljump is a video game knowledge reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of Dbljump is this: &lt;strong&gt;one place on the Internet with everything you want to know about video games and the games industry&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020/06/person-article-mobile-th.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-right&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closest thing we have to that now is Wikipedia. Which is amazing, of course. It has a brilliant community and content. The problem with Wikipedia is that it doesn’t have trailers and screens. It doesn’t structure data in ways you can analyse, or help you join the dots between games, people, and companies. It’s a general reference, not one dedicated to gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few game databases around too. They’re like gaming versions of IMDb. But none of them has ever gained much traction because none is quite right. Some fail on presentation. Some prioritise quantity over quality, trying to catalogue every game ever created. Others are mere scrapers, which don’t add much value to the data they collect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dbljump is our answer to this problem. Our mission is to make it the best gaming reference in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;which-features-are-in-the-dbljump-alpha-whats-coming-in-the-future&quot;&gt;Which features are in the Dbljump alpha? What’s coming in the future?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dbljump combines &lt;strong&gt;the encyclopaedia-style content of Wikipedia with the structured data of a database&lt;/strong&gt;. And it’s our goal to present everything beautifully. (We aren’t there yet and we’d love your feedback.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re launching in an “alpha” state. That’s the stage before beta, i.e. early days. It’s functional, but it doesn’t have all the features we’re planning yet. There will definitely be bugs. Almost everything has room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At launch Dbljump editors will be able to create articles about…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games&lt;/strong&gt; including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform versions&lt;/strong&gt; with technical details (e.g. frame-rate and resolution)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Releases&lt;/strong&gt; for each version with dates, places, and basic media types&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genres&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company and staff credits&lt;/strong&gt; with options to specify version and place (e.g. the publisher of the Nintendo Switch version in North America)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Images&lt;/strong&gt; including screenshots, box arts, art, and more; you can specify a version, place, date, and add the proper attributions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aliases&lt;/strong&gt; with options to specify place, kind (e.g. working titles), writing system (e.g. Japanese, Chinese, Cyrillic, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;, which are Dbljump’s categorised, encyclopaedia-like text with references; categories for game notes include development, story, and cultural impact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People&lt;/strong&gt; including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal details&lt;/strong&gt; like date and place of birth/death, and aliases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game credits&lt;/strong&gt; including role, place and version where appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Images&lt;/strong&gt; including photos and artworks; as with game images, you can specify a version, place, date, and add the proper attributions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt; with references, so you can provide biographical detail; categories for people include biography, education, and career&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Companies&lt;/strong&gt; including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company details&lt;/strong&gt; like locations, founding and closing dates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationships&lt;/strong&gt; between organisations, past and present; so we can link divisions and subsidiaries to their parents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aliases&lt;/strong&gt; so we can chart name changes and names in different places, writing systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credits&lt;/strong&gt; including role, place and version where appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Images&lt;/strong&gt; including logos, photos, document scans and more; like with people images, you can specify a version, place, date, and add the proper attributions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt; with references, so you can provide historic detail; categories for companies include history, technologies, and products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plan to add new features including videos, game character articles, awards, and sales figures. Game platforms will become first-class articles with their own images, notes, and platform-specific data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can tell us which features are important via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and our Discord (opening soon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020/06/platforms-dashboard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Search, filter, add and edit game platforms&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Search, filter, add and edit game platforms

    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;which-topics-are-notable-enough&quot;&gt;Which topics are notable enough?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dbljump editors can create articles about &lt;strong&gt;whichever games, people and companies you want&lt;/strong&gt;. If you love 90s Sega arcades, try forming a group around that. If you want to be first to put together info and media about newly announced games, do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020/06/companies-dash-mobile-th.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-left&quot; class=&quot;align-left&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re focused on gaming. Many games, people, and companies that aren’t notable enough for Wikipedia are welcome here. Our tools and presentation are specialised for gaming topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you love a particular gaming niche, or you’re a fan of an under-appreciated game director or company, you can use Dbljump to shine a light on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re not here to robotically input every retro game&lt;/strong&gt;. We believe the topics our community wants to &lt;em&gt;write&lt;/em&gt; about are likely the topics the wider audience wants to &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt; about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, we want you to enjoy contributing to Dbljump - this is for fun, not work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-become-a-dbljump-editor&quot;&gt;How to become a Dbljump editor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sign-up is opening  soon and I’ll update this post when it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, please feel free to ask questions and let us know what you think. You can do that via our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dbljumpgames&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re really excited about finally launching Dbljump. We hope you’ll support us as we work to build a gaming reference we can all enjoy and be proud of!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Neil Wheatley</name></author><summary type="html">Learn more about what's in the Dbljump video game reference at launch, and what makes it different, in our first blog post.</summary></entry></feed>